Guide to the Vassar College Archives Files, circa 1855-1969 (bulk 1860-1914)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (2), 1872-1880 (Box 10, Folder 6.81)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (3), 1881-1886 (Box 10, Folder 6.82)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (4), 1886-1888 (Box 10, Folder 6.83)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (5), 1889-1891 (Box 10, Folder 6.84)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (6), 1892-1893 (Box 10, Folder 6.85)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (7), 1893-1894 (Box 10, Folder 6.86)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (8), 1895-1896 (Box 10, Folder 6.87)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (9), 1897-1899 (Box 10, Folder 6.88)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (10), 1900-1901 (Box 10, Folder 6.89)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Report (11), 1902-1909 (Box 10, Folder 6.90)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Celebration of the 25th Anniversary (Box 10, Folder 6.91)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Duties of the Standing Committee, 1864 (Box 10, Folder 6.92)
- Trustees — Cabinets and Apparatus Engineers (Box 10, Folder 6.93)
- Trustees — Executive Committee (Box 10, Folder 6.94)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1861 Feb - 1862 Mar (Box 10, Folder 6.95)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1862 Mar - 1864 Jun (Box 10, Folder 6.96)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1864 Jun - 1866 Jul (Box 10, Folder 6.97)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1880-1913 (Box 10, Folder 6.98)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1888-1890 (Box 10, Folder 6.99)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 6.100)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes, 1892 (Box 10, Folder 6.101)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes Report, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 7.1)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Minutes Report, 1888 (Box 10, Folder 7.2)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Report (includes letters to committee), 1861-1869 (Box 10, Folder 7.3)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Reports (also correspondence), 1888-1893 (Box 10, Folder 7.4)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Reports (also correspondence), 1894-1904 (Box 10, Folder 7.5)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Reports (also correspondence), 1905-1914 (Box 10, Folder 7.6)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Reports, 1917-1918 (Box 10, Folder 7.7)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Report (includes letters to committee), 1870-1874 (Box 10, Folder 7.8)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Report (includes letters to committee), 1875-1876 (Box 10, Folder 7.9)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Report, 1887-1882 (Box 10, Folder 7.10)
- Trustees — Executive Committee Report, 1883-1886, 1889 (Box 10, Folder 7.11)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies (Box 10, Folder 7.12)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Proceedings, 1866-1884 (Box 10, Folder 7.13)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Report (memoranda, letters, etc.), 1861, 1866 (Box 10, Folder 7.14)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Report, 1867-1872 (Box 10, Folder 7.15)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Report, 1873-1883 (Box 11, Folder 7.16)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Report, 1884-1898 (Box 11, Folder 7.17)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Report, 1899-1907 (Box 11, Folder 7.18)
- Trustees — Committee on Faculty and Studies Report, 1908-1914 (Box 11, Folder 7.19)
- Trustees — Finance Committee Report (Committee on Investment), 1871-1876 (Box 11, Folder 7.20)
- Trustees — Finance Committee Report (Committee on Finance), 1875-1892 (Box 11, Folder 7.21)
- Trustees — Finance Committee Report (Committee on Securities), 1870-1904 (Box 11, Folder 7.22)
- Trustees — Finance Committee Report (Committee on Securities), 1905-1914 (Box 11, Folder 7.23)
- Trustees — Finance Committee Report (Committee on Finance and Securities) (Box 11, Folder 7.24)
- Trustees — Committee on Future Policies. Correspondence of Dr. Taylor, 1893-1894 (Box 11, Folder 7.25)
- Trustees — Committee on Grounds, 1912-1919 (Box 11, Folder 7.26)
- Trustees — Committee on Grounds, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 7.27)
- Trustees — Committee on Investment, 1916-1917 (Box 11, Folder 7.28)
- Trustees — Committee on Investment Reports of the Committee of Investment and Finance, 1930-1936 (Box 11, Folder 7.29)
- Trustees — Committee on Investment Reports of the Committee of Sage Fund, 1921-1934 (Box 11, Folder 7.30)
- Trustees — Committee on Library, 1861-1871 (Box 11, Folder 7.31)
- Trustees — Committee on Library, 1872-1882 (Box 11, Folder 7.32)
- Trustees — Committee on Library, 1883-1899 (Box 11, Folder 7.33)
- Trustees — Committee on Library, 1900-1913 (Box 11, Folder 7.34)
- Trustees — Committee on Museum and Laboratories, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 7.35)
- Trustees — Committee on Museum and Laboratories, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 7.36)
- Trustees — Committee on Music Department Equipment (Box 11, Folder 7.37)
- Trustees — Committee on Nomination of Trustees, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 7.38)
- Trustees — Committee on Powers and Duties of Officers, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 7.39)
- Trustees — Committee on Professors' Houses and Salaries, 1882-1893 (Box 11, Folder 7.40)
- Trustees — Committee on Retrenchment, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 7.41)
- Trustees — Committee on Scholarships Report, 1868-1889 (Box 11, Folder 7.42)
- Trustees — Committee on Scholarships Report, 1889-1911 (Box 11, Folder 7.43)
- Trustees — Committee on Selection of a President, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 7.44)
- Trustees — Special Committee Reports, 1867-1869 (Box 11, Folder 7.45)
- Trustees — Special Committee Reports, 1875-1911 (Box 11, Folder 7.46)
- Trustees — Special Committee Reports, 1883-1904 (Box 11, Folder 7.47)
- Trustees — Special Committee on Expenditures, 1885 Jun (Box 11, Folder 7.48)
- Trustees — Special Committee on Reorganization: Business Departments, 1909-1910 (Box 11, Folder 7.49)
- Trustees — Special Committee on Reorganization: Educational Departments, 1911-1912 (Box 11, Folder 7.50)
- Trustees — Special Committee on Ways and Means (Box 11, Folder 7.51)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1861-1868 (Box 11, Folder 7.52)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1869-1882 (Box 11, Folder 7.53)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1883-1885 (Box 11, Folder 7.54)
- Trustees — Correspondence (Mary H. Whitney, pensions), 1910-1912 (Box 11, Folder 7.55)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1888-1890 (Box 11, Folder 7.56)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1891-1895 (Box 11, Folder 7.57)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1896-1902 (Box 11, Folder 7.58)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1905-1907 (Box 11, Folder 7.59)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1908-1910 (Box 11, Folder 7.60)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1909-1913 (Box 11, Folder 7.61)
- Trustees — Correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 11, Folder 7.62)
- Trustees — Distribution of Powers and Duties p. 46, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 7.63)
- Trustees — Distribution of Powers and Duties, p. 46-7 and Portfolio of Plans (Box 11, Folder 7.64)
- Trustees — First Meeting:, 1861 Feb 26 (Box 11, Folder 7.65)
- Trustees — Regular Meetings, 1903-1920 (Box 11, Folder 7.66)
- Trustees — Meeting, 1865 Apr 12 (Box 11, Folder 7.67)
- Trustees — Meetings, 1862-1863 (Box 11, Folder 7.68)
- Trustees — Meetings, 1864 (Box 11, Folder 7.69)
- Trustees — Special Meeting, 1918, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 7.70)
- Trustees — Minutes (includes petitions to board, reports of other business), 1867-1878 (Box 12, Folder 7.71)
- Trustees — Minutes (includes petitions to board, reports of other business), 1877-1885 (Box 12, Folder 7.72)
- Trustees — Minutes, 1897-1899 (Box 12, Folder 7.73)
- Trustees — Minutes, 1900-1909 (Box 12, Folder 7.74)
- Trustees — Minutes, 1893-1896, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 7.75)
- Trustees — Minutes, 1892 (Box 12, Folder 7.76)
- Trustees — Minutes, 1886-1889 (Box 12, Folder 7.77)
- Trustees — Minutes, 1889-1891 (Box 12, Folder 7.78)
- Trustees — Name Change (Box 12, Folder 7.79)
- Trustees — Organization, Plans for 1864-1865 (Box 12, Folder 7.80)
- Trustees — Property Real and Personal (Box 12, Folder 7.81)
- Trustees — Sale of Property, 1904-1905 (Box 12, Folder 7.82)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1861-1862 (Box 12, Folder 7.83)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1867-1868 (Box 12, Folder 7.84)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1869-1871 (Box 12, Folder 7.85)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1872-1874 (Box 12, Folder 7.86)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1872-1873 (Box 12, Folder 7.87)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1876-1884 (Box 12, Folder 7.88)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1885-1887 (Box 12, Folder 7.89)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1888, 1890-1892 (Box 12, Folder 7.90)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1893-1897 (Box 12, Folder 7.91)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1898-1902 (Box 12, Folder 7.92)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1905-1907 (Box 12, Folder 7.93)
- Trustees — Resolutions, 1908-1913 (Box 12, Folder 7.94)
- Trustees — Resolutions Women Trustees (Box 12, Folder 7.95)
- Trustees — Resolutions Women Trustees (Box 12, Folder 7.96)
- Trustees — Resolutions Tuitions (Box 12, Folder 7.97)
- Trustees — Resolutions Tyler, Moses Coit (Box 12, Folder 7.98)
- Trustees — Resolutions Vacations (Box 12, Folder 7.99)
- Van Ingen, Henry — Correspondence, 1868-1869, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 9.36)
- Vassar, Matthew — Autograph album pages, [2 leaves, 1 framed leaf] (Box 13, Folder 8.44)
- Vassar College and Its Founder — Correspondence acknowledging gift copies (Box 12, Folder 7.100)
- Vassar Students' Aid Society (Box 12, Folder 7.101)
- Vassariana — Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 7.102)
- War Activities (Box 12, Folder 7.103)
- Warden's Office (Box 12, Folder 7.106)
- Wolven, Edmund L. (Box 12, Folder 7.104)
- Wood, Frances A. (Box 12, Folder 7.105)
- Wood, Nathan E. — (VC Trustee) - Resignation letter to James M. Taylor, 1903 May 15 (Box 15, Folder 9.37)
- Zoology Department, [SEE ALSO: Natural History Department] (Box 12, Folder 7.107)
- Archives Photographs — Raymond Ave. (Box 12, Folder 8.1)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Buildings. Calisthenium and Riding Academy (Box 12, Folder 8.2)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Buildings. Chapel (Box 12, Folder 8.3)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Buildings. Lodge (Box 12, Folder 8.4)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Buildings. Main (Box 12, Folder 8.5)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Buildings. Observatory. Exterior (Box 12, Folder 8.6)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Buildings Observatory. Interior (Box 12, Folder 8.7)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Class Groups. Academic (Art) (Box 12, Folder 8.8)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Class Groups. Academic (Astronomy) (Box 12, Folder 8.9)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Class Groups. Academic (Greek) (Box 12, Folder 8.10)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Class Groups. Academic (Physics) (Box 12, Folder 8.11)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Faculty. Early A-L (Box 12, Folder 8.12a)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Faculty. Early A-L (Box 13, Folder 8.12b)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Faculty Early M-Z (Box 13, Folders 8.13a-8.13b)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Physicians (Box 13, Folder 8.13c)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Presidents (Box 13, Folder 8.14)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Student and Faculty Rooms, 1870s (Box 13, Folder 8.15)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Students, Misc. Groups. Early (Box 13, Folder 8.16)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Students, Resolutes [baseball club], circa 1876 (Box 13, Folder 8.17)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Trustees (Box 13, Folder 8.18)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Vassar Lake (Box 13, Folder 8.19)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Vassar, Matthew, Buildings Related to (Box 13, Folder 8.20)
- Archives Photographs — V. C. Vassar, Matthew, Relatives (Box 13, Folder 8.21)
- [NOTE: Archival Photographs — for office use only, copies in Photograph Files]
- Archival Photographs — Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Calendar (Box 13, Folder 8.22)
- Archival Photographs — Engraved Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Buttre engraving (Box 13, Folder 8.23)
- Archival Photographs — Engraved Portraits. Matthew Vassar, H. Wright Smith engraving, [1865-1867?] (Box 13, Folder 8.24)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, at desk, [1835-1840?] (Box 13, Folder 8.25)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Bogle miniature, [circa 1855?] (Box 13, Folder 8.26)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Booth miniature (Box 13, Folder 8.27)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, early oil portrait (Box 13, Folder 8.28)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Elliott portrait, 1861 (Box 13, Folder 8.29)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, oval portrait (Box 13, Folder 8.30)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, seated portrait with curved cane (Box 13, Folder 8.31)
- Archival Photographs — Painted Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Wright portrait, 1861 (Box 13, Folder 8.32)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, daguerreotype (Box 13, Folder 8.33)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, daguerreotypes, 2 in top hat (Box 13, Folder 8.34)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, "Fund Box" Pictures (Box 13, Folder 8.35)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, late portrait, circa 1867-[1868?] (Box 13, Folder 8.36)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, seated, holding spectacles (Box 13, Folder 8.37)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, standing by pillar, [1867 Jan 25] (Box 13, Folder 8.38)
- Archival Photographs — Photographic Portraits. Matthew Vassar, with dog "Tip" (Box 13, Folder 8.39)
- Archival Photographs — Silhouette Portraits. Matthew Vassar, full length (Box 13, Folder 8.40)
- Archival Photographs — Silhouette Portraits. Matthew Vassar, head (Box 13, Folder 8.41)
- Archival Photographs — Sculptural Portraits. Matthew Vassar, proposed statue and bust (Hoffman) (Box 13, Folder 8.42)
- Archival Photographs — Miscellaneous Portraits. Matthew Vassar, Misc. Undated Pictures (Box 13, Folder 8.43)
- Archival Photographs — "Vassar Female College" illustration from Harper's Weekly (1861 Mar 30), undated; [1 photograph] (Box 13, Folder 8.45)
- Archival Prints — Matthew Vassar portrait by C. Buttre, with accompanying letter from the South Kensington Museum to M. P. Jewett, 1862 May 20 (Box 13, Folder 8.46)